<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robert Dunne</title>
    <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Robert Dunne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://robbiejdunne.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Expected Passing at Euro 2020</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-passing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-passing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There is a dearth of public work on passing probabilities in football. Several companies and teams have carried out analysis of passing probability in football, but they are not publicly available. For example, Opta have their own expected passing model which they call xP (‘Introducing Expected Pass Completion (xP)’, 2021). The variables they use include:
x-coordinate of pass start location mirrored y-coordinate of pass start location (e.g. so a pass played from the left edge of the penalty area and a pass played from the right edge of the penalty area would both take the value 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the NFL Draft</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/predicting-nfl-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/predicting-nfl-draft/</guid>
      <description>Another project for college. I wanted to predict the NFL Draft using historical data. This was a large project that involved a lot of scraping and cleaning data and a lot of modelling.
You see all the code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL Expected Rushing Yards</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-rushing-yards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 14:26:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-rushing-yards/</guid>
      <description>The nflverse is pretty amazing. So is Shiny, if not a little tricky to figure out. I decided to combine the two to create an Expected Rushing Yards model that would publish the results through Shiny.
The main goal of this project was to create a Shiny app with multiple pages and a navigation bar. Therefore, the model the rushing yards are predicted using is linear regression with rushing yards, down and seconds remaining in the half as the variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a data enthusiast - especially as it relates to my other hobbies {sport, books, music, movies}. I mostly code in R, Python and Javascript. I also develop apps using Shiny, React, Node, Gatsby and others.
How do I know what I think until I see what I say. This is somewhere I can write about different aspects of the technology that I use and my other interests. You can have a look at some of the things I have written here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/writing/</guid>
      <description>I have written for various sites during my career. I write regularly about Atlético Madrid here.
I also write a LaLiga blog here.
A lot of the other work I write about is here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
