<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robert Dunne</title>
    <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Robert Dunne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 14:26:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://robbiejdunne.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indie Song Generator</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/indie-song-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 14:26:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/indie-song-generator/</guid>
      <description>I decided to pick my ten favourite musicians using Spotify&amp;rsquo;s developer tools, scrape the lyrics using Genius&amp;rsquo; API and then create a song using Markovify.
According to Spotify, my top ten bands of all time are.
So I used Python to scrape Genius and came back with a file.
Markovify is a library that. You can read more about it here&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expected Passing</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-passing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-passing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the NFL Draft</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/predicting-nfl-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/predicting-nfl-draft/</guid>
      <description>Another project for college. I wanted to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL Expected Rushing Yards</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-rushing-yards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 14:26:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/posts/projects/expected-rushing-yards/</guid>
      <description>The nflverse is pretty amazing. So is Shiny, if not a little tricky to figure out. I decided to combine the two to create an Expected Rushing Yards model that would publish the results through Shiny.
The main goal of this project was to create a Shiny app with multiple pages and a navigation bar. Therefore, the model the rushing yards are predicted using is linear regression with rushing yards, down and seconds remaining in the half as the variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I like data - especially as it relates to my other hobbies {sport, books, music, movies}. I mostly code in R, Python and Javascript. I also develop apps using Shiny, React, Node, Gatsby and others.
I write too. You can have a look at some of the things I have written here.
Please feel free to get in touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robbiejdunne.github.io/writing/</guid>
      <description>I have written for various sites during my career. I write regularly about Atlético Madrid here.
I also write a LaLiga blog here.
A lot of the other work I write about is here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
